getholistichealth.com 2019-07-31

# Privacy Policy - Get Holistic Health

**Privacy Policy**

 **Who We Are**

This Privacy Policy explains how **Get Holistic Health** _(‘we’ or ‘us’ or ‘our’)_ collects, uses, stores, retains and discloses your personal information (also referred to as “personal data”) in connection with the use of [www.getholistichealth.com](https://www.getholistichealth.com/) (hereafter the “site”) as well as provide information regarding your rights to access and control the information we collect or hold about you. This policy also sets out the steps we agree to so as to comply with the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and other applicable data protection laws. Please review this Policy carefully because it applies to personal information we process about you. If you do not agree with our data processing activities in connection with your use of this site, we have provided a number of opt-out mechanisms for you to control the collection and information you make available to us. Please note that you also have the option not to use the site.

 **Information That We Collect**

To provide our services and products and to supply information, **Get Holistic Health** may collect and use certain personal information from you. We also process personal information in order to fulfill our obligations under the law or any contract between you and Get Holistic Health. As a general policy, we do not collect information without lawful ground to do and we do not process your information in any way, other than as specified in this policy.

The personal information that we collect from you is:

  * Name
  * Date of Birth
  * Home Address
  * Personal or business Email
  * Telephone Number
  * IP address

 **We collect information in the following ways:**

While we do not automatically collect personal information, we will collect it when you contact us directly via email or contact forms on the website. We will also collect your email if you subscribe to our newsletter. If you register at the site, we will collect certain personal information provided by you. When you visit the site, our web server will also log certain online identifiers that could reasonably likely identify you as a natural person. This include the domain address of your internet service (IP address), the type of device you are using, the type of browser you are using, pages viewed, date and time of visit, duration spent on the website as well as the website that linked you to content or resource on our website.

 **Legal Basis for Processing (How We Use Your Personal Data)  
**

**Get Holistic Health** respects user privacy and, unless required to do so by law, we will under no circumstances disclose your information without your clear and verifiable consent.  We will only keep your information for as long as is necessary and for the purpose(s) stated in this policy. Where you have consented to us providing you with special offers, news, updates and information relating to site activities, please note that you may withdraw your consent at any time and opt-out of those data collection activities. The lawful grounds that we rely for processing your personal data are detailed below: –

  *  **Performance of contract:** We may collect your personal data which is necessary for the performance of any agreement to provide service to you or to fulfil any request submitted by you before entering the contract. We will use that information to ensure that products or information you request can be sent out to your preferred address. We will use information you provide when you contact us to respond to your inquiries.
  *  **Compliance of Legal Obligation:** We collect, use and retain personal data as necessary for complying with any legal obligation to which Get Holistic Health is subject including for example for business accounting and tax purposes, complying with a lawful request by law enforcement or public authority.
  *  **Consent:** we process your personal data if you expressly opt-in to provide it in relation to your use of our services and website.
  *  **Legitimate Interests:** We will process your information so as to send you marketing information on the basis of an existing business relationship with you and if we have deemed that it is beneficial to you as a customer and in our legitimate interests including for example information on nutrition, mental health, weight loss, muscle building and other health related topics.

 **Cookies and Similar technologies** :

We use cookies to process information that helps us to personalize user experience and improve the overall design and functionality of our website. A cookie is tiny text file which a web server asks to store in the user’s device. Cookies contain random text and generally anonymous identifiers from the originating site. Cookies are only placed on your device’s internet browser if your device is set to accept cookies.  As a provider of overall health-related information, cookies help us to remember user actions on the site and offer content that is more relevant to you.

Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and make use of personal information. The following outlines our Privacy Policy.

When accessing our Website, **Get Holistic Health** will learn certain information about you during your visit.

Similar to other commercial Web sites, our Web site utilizes a standard technology called cookies (see explanation below, What Are Cookies?) and Web server logs to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site, your IP address.

 **Get Holistic Health** uses **Google AdSense** to deliver targeted ads. Google AdSense uses information about you from other sites to personalize and deliver ads on our website. Where we use third parties to process data on our behalf, we ensure that they process data in accordance with instructions from us and comply fully with this privacy Policy, the applicable data protection laws and any other appropriate confidentiality and security obligation.

 ** ** **DoubleClick Cookie**  
****

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website.
  * Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [ads preference manager](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). (Alternatively, you can direct users to opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).)

 ** **You can read more about Google’s Advertising and Cookies here:[http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/)****

 **What Are Cookies?**

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a Web site, that site’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each Web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a Web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

 **Third party cookies**  
We use third party services that may set cookies on your device. We use Double-click cookie which is developed by Google to display ads on our website, control how often ads are shown to you, as well as personalize ads basing  on user’s previous interaction with our website or other websites that use the double-click cookie. Double-click cookie may collect your IP address and browser information. We do not collect personal information using third party cookies and we do not combine or associate information collected by double-click cookie with any personal information about you. Please note that you can opt-out of the use of Double-Click cookie by visiting Google’s Help pages and privacy policy.  For additional information about opting out interest based advertising, please visit [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/)

 **IP Addresses**

Your computer uses IP addresses every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as “traffic data” so that data (such as the Web pages you request) can be sent to you.

 **Email Information**

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received online, mail and telephone.

 **How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?**

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing customer service and making available other items and services to our customers and prospective customers.

 **Get Holistic Health** will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us, nor will such information be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties without the approval of the user at the time of collection.  
We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights.

 **Children’s Online Privacy.**  
Our services are meant for persons over the age of 13 and we will not intentionally collect information from persons under the age of 13 (minors). If you are minor, we ask you not to submit any personal information to us and you must obtain valid and verifiable consent of your parent or guardian to use the site.

 ** _Your Rights_**

You have the right to access  and control any personal information that **Get Holistic Health** processes about you and to request information about: –

  * What personal data we hold about you
  * The purposes of the processing
  * The categories of personal data concerned
  * The recipients to whom the personal data has/will be disclosed
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source

If you think that information we hold about you is erroneous or lacking in any way, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete the information and we will do our best to do so as quickly as practicable; unless there is a valid reason for not doing so. You also have the right to:

  * request erasure of your personal data.
  * restrict processing in accordance with the data protection laws
  * object to any direct marketing from us
  * Transmit your data to different service providers (data portability)

To ensure security and privacy of personal data, Get Holistic Health may demand additional verification before acting on any data access right request from you

 **Sharing and Disclosing Your Personal Information**

We do not share or disclose any of your personal information without your consent, other than for the purposes specified in this Privacy Policy and as otherwise permitted or required by law.

 **How Do We Protect Your Information and Secure Information Transmissions?**

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. However, doing so is allowed, but at your own risk. Some of the information you may enter on our Web site may be transmitted securely via a secure medium known as Secure Sockets Layer, or SSL. Credit Card information is never transmitted via email.

 **Get Holistic Health** may use software programs to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.  
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, **Get Holistic Health** uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

 **Safeguarding Measures**

Security and integrity of personal data is of great importance to us.   To prevent accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access to, personal data transmitted, stored or otherwise processed  by us , we have implemented several measures to protect and secure your personal data including industry standard encryption (TLS-AES 128-bit encryption), pseudonymisation and anonymization of personal data, user authentication as well as role and attribute- based access controls.

 **Transfers Outside the EU**

 **Get Holistic Health** uses some products or services that may be hosted or stored outside of the EU. These services include email servers and marketing database. This means that we may transfer certain information submitted by you through the website outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). You should therefore be aware when you sign up or subscribe to our newsletter that the personal information you supply may be stored on servers which are hosted outside of EU. Where data is processed outside of EU, we will make sure that those providers use the necessary level of protection for your information and comply with data protection policy set out by **Get Holistic Health** as well as the relevant data protection laws.

 **Failure to Provide Data or Consent _  
_**  
While you are obligated to provide any personal data, Get Holistic Health will need consent to process your personal data to provide specific services requested by you. If consent is necessary is required for us to be able to provide our service or products to, we may not be able to provide such service or product if your consent is withheld or withdrawn

 **Legitimate Interests**

From time to time we may process your personal information under the legitimate interests’ legal basis.  To comply with the GDPR, we will always carry out a thorough Legitimate Interests’ Assessment to identify the potential risks to your rights and freedoms. If the risk to your rights is great, we will not process data on this basis. We use the legitimate interests’ legal basis for processing of website usage data so as to understand website usage, deliver personalized content and provide the design and structure of the site.

 **How Long We Keep Your Data**

 **Get Holistic Health** only keeps personal information for as long as is necessary and we have designed a firm data retention policy so as to comply with these obligations. We may keep your personal details for the duration allowed by law after which time it will be erased. If you subscribe to our newsletter and provide consent, we will keep your data for that purpose until you opt-out or withdraw your consent

 **CONSENT EXAMPLE**

From time to time, **Get Holistic Health** would like to contact you with the special offers, promotions, competitions, and product news that we provide. If you consent to us using your contact information for this purpose, you have the right to withdraw it at any time by using the opt-out/unsubscribe mechanisms we provide or by contacting Get Holistic Health directly.

 **Lodging A Complaint**

 **Get Holistic Health** only collects and uses your personal information in compliance with this privacy policy and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If you have a complaint with respect to our data processing activities including how we handle your requests to access and control of information we hold about you, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.

 **Policy Changes**

We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without notice. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, without your prior consent.

We are committed to conducting our business in accordance with these principles in order to ensure that the confidentiality of personal information is protected and maintained.

 **Request My Data**

Contact us about if we are using your data.

 **Contact**

If you have any questions regarding this Policy, or your dealings with our web site, please [contact us](https://www.getholistichealth.com/contact-us-2/).

 **Get Holistic Health Paid Advertising  
**

Paid advertising on Get Holistic Health may not represent the views and opinions of this website and its contributors. No endorsement of products and services advertised is either expressed or implied.
